<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-02-23T15:34:23-06:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lu Jing</title><subtitle>Lu Jing, Postdoc at Northwestern University, PhD in computational geomechanics, geophysical fluid dynamics, and granular physics. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Granular segregation: from particle-scale physics to continuum theory</title><link href="/research/2022/02/23/segregation-force.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Granular segregation: from particle-scale physics to continuum theory" /><published>2022-02-23T00:50:40-06:00</published><updated>2022-02-23T00:50:40-06:00</updated><id>/research/2022/02/23/segregation-force</id><content type="html" xml:base="/research/2022/02/23/segregation-force.html">&lt;p&gt;This research aims to advance fundamental understanding of granular segregation at the particle level and enhance predictive modeling of size and/or density segregation across various flow configurations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first result is how large and small particles migrate at the particle scale, hinting at completely different physics &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#jing_micromechanical_2017&quot;&gt;(Jing et al., 2017)&lt;/a&gt;. Based on this microscopic understanding, a bottom-up theoretical model is developed to describe the net force driving segregation in terms of particle properties (size ratio, density ratio) and local flow conditions (pressure, shear rate, and their gradients), which unifies two major driving mechanisms of segregation – gravity and shear-induced gradients &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#jing_unified_2021&quot;&gt;(Jing et al., 2021)&lt;/a&gt;. The force model is shown to accurately predict the segregation direction, over a wide range of conditions, in various flow configurations &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#jing_rising_2020&quot;&gt;(Jing et al., 2020; Jing et al., 2021)&lt;/a&gt;. Recently, our model is extended to provide closure relations for segregation modeling in continuum granular flow theories &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#duan_segregation_2022&quot;&gt;(Duan et al., 2022)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The findings are expected to serve as the backbone of radically new methods for predicting and even controlling segregation in industrial and geophysical applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;jing_micromechanical_2017&quot;&gt;Jing, L., Kwok, C. Y., &amp;amp; Leung, Y. F. (2017). Micromechanical origin of particle size segregation. &lt;i&gt;Physical Review Letters&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;118&lt;/i&gt;(11), 118001. https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.118001&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;jing_unified_2021&quot;&gt;Jing, L., Ottino, J. M., Lueptow, R. M., &amp;amp; Umbanhowar, P. B. (2021). A unified description of gravity- and kinematics-induced segregation forces in dense granular flows. &lt;i&gt;Journal of Fluid Mechanics&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;925&lt;/i&gt;, A29. https://doi.org/10.1017/jfm.2021.688&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;jing_rising_2020&quot;&gt;Jing, L., Ottino, J. M., Lueptow, R. M., &amp;amp; Umbanhowar, P. B. (2020). Rising and sinking intruders in dense granular flows. &lt;i&gt;Physical Review Research&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;2&lt;/i&gt;(2), 022069. https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevResearch.2.022069&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;duan_segregation_2022&quot;&gt;Duan, Y., Jing, L., Umbanhowar, P. B., Ottino, J. M., &amp;amp; Lueptow, R. M. (2022). Segregation forces in dense granular ﬂows: Closing the gap between single intruders and mixtures. &lt;i&gt;Journal of Fluid Mechanics&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;935&lt;/i&gt;, R1. https://doi.org/10.1017/jfm.2022.12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;!-- [1]: [,&quot;blog/2017/01/03/phd-thesis.html&quot;] --&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This research aims to advance fundamental understanding of granular segregation at the particle level and enhance predictive modeling of size and/or density segregation across various flow configurations.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rate-dependent sliding laws for long-runout granular avalanches</title><link href="/none/2018/04/06/sliding-law.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rate-dependent sliding laws for long-runout granular avalanches " /><published>2018-04-06T00:40:12-05:00</published><updated>2018-04-06T00:40:12-05:00</updated><id>/none/2018/04/06/sliding-law</id><content type="html" xml:base="/none/2018/04/06/sliding-law.html">&lt;p&gt;Characterization of slip velocity for granular flows over inclines of different geometric roughness, ranging from flat to bumpy. Modeling the frictional boundary behaviors as rate-dependent sliding laws; that is, the basal shear stress is proportional to the basal normal stress by a factor (i.e., the basal friction coefficient) that depends on local shear rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- This project aims to understand the effect of base roughness in granular flows. The
geometric roughness of a base made of spheres is first characterized, with a wide range
of particle size and packing arrangement (check out [here][1]). 

[1]: http://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevE.94.052901  --&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Characterization of slip velocity for granular flows over inclines of different geometric roughness, ranging from flat to bumpy. Modeling the frictional boundary behaviors as rate-dependent sliding laws; that is, the basal shear stress is proportional to the basal normal stress by a factor (i.e., the basal friction coefficient) that depends on local shear rates.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dynamics of immersed granular flows</title><link href="/none/2017/03/17/immersed-granular-flow.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dynamics of immersed granular flows" /><published>2017-03-17T07:20:51-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-17T07:20:51-05:00</updated><id>/none/2017/03/17/immersed-granular-flow</id><content type="html" xml:base="/none/2017/03/17/immersed-granular-flow.html">&lt;p&gt;This research aims to understand the dynamics of immersed granular flow. We use both coarse-grid and fully-resolved fluid-particle coupling approaches, combined with small-scale laboratory experiments, to look at granular column collapses in a viscous fluid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many parameters control the dynamics of immersed granular flow, including particle size, particle density, fluid density, fluid viscosity, column aspect ratio &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#jing_dynamics_2018&quot;&gt;(Jing et al., 2018)&lt;/a&gt; and column packing density &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#yang_pore_2020&quot;&gt;(Yang et al., 2020)&lt;/a&gt;. We are seeking for dimensionless parameters combining the effects of all these parameters, which are expect to capture different flow regimes where distinct flow dynamics are observed &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#jing_flow_2019&quot;&gt;(Jing et al., 2019)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;jing_dynamics_2018&quot;&gt;Jing, L., Yang, G. C., Kwok, C. Y., &amp;amp; Sobral, Y. D. (2018). Dynamics and scaling laws of underwater granular collapse with varying aspect ratios. &lt;i&gt;Physical Review E&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;98&lt;/i&gt;(4), 042901. https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevE.98.042901&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;yang_pore_2020&quot;&gt;Yang, G. C., Jing, L., Kwok, C. Y., &amp;amp; Sobral, Y. D. (2020). Pore-scale simulation of immersed granular collapse: Implications to submarine landslides. &lt;i&gt;Journal of Geophysical Research: Earth Surface&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;125&lt;/i&gt;(1), e2019JF005044. https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JF005044&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;jing_flow_2019&quot;&gt;Jing, L., Yang, G. C., Kwok, C. Y., &amp;amp; Sobral, Y. D. (2019). Flow regimes and dynamic similarity of immersed granular collapse: A CFD-DEM investigation. &lt;i&gt;Powder Technology&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;345&lt;/i&gt;, 532–543. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.powtec.2019.01.029&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This research aims to understand the dynamics of immersed granular flow. We use both coarse-grid and fully-resolved fluid-particle coupling approaches, combined with small-scale laboratory experiments, to look at granular column collapses in a viscous fluid.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Graphic overview of PhD thesis: Unraveling micromechanics of debris flow mobility</title><link href="/research/2017/02/28/phd-thesis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Graphic overview of PhD thesis: Unraveling micromechanics of debris flow mobility" /><published>2017-02-28T20:00:55-06:00</published><updated>2017-02-28T20:00:55-06:00</updated><id>/research/2017/02/28/phd-thesis</id><content type="html" xml:base="/research/2017/02/28/phd-thesis.html">&lt;p&gt;My PhD research is focused on the physics of debris flow mobility. Here is a graphic overview of my &lt;a href=&quot;https://hub.hku.hk/handle/10722/241402&quot;&gt;thesis&lt;/a&gt;, which is also a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.civil.hku.hk/newsletter/newsletter2017feb.pdf&quot;&gt;newsletter cover&lt;/a&gt; for the Department of Civil Engineering, HKU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/files/overview.png&quot; alt=&quot;research_overview&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;width: 800px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The debris flow sketch is adapted from Alessandro Leonardi’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.3929/ethz-a-010542711&quot;&gt;thesis&lt;/a&gt; with permission.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">My PhD research is focused on the physics of debris flow mobility. Here is a graphic overview of my thesis, which is also a newsletter cover for the Department of Civil Engineering, HKU.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Effects of base roughness in granular flows down inclines</title><link href="/none/2016/12/20/base-roughness.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Effects of base roughness in granular flows down inclines" /><published>2016-12-20T06:20:51-06:00</published><updated>2016-12-20T06:20:51-06:00</updated><id>/none/2016/12/20/base-roughness</id><content type="html" xml:base="/none/2016/12/20/base-roughness.html">&lt;p&gt;One way that a granular flow differs from ordinary fluids is that its dynamics depends
largely on the conditions at solid boundaries. For instance, the minimum thickness
necessary to sustain a steady flow is a function of base roughness;
the slip occurring at the base can modify the bulk rheological behavior, which changes
the disorder flow state to a crystallized structure. Such a complicated dependency on solid boundaries in
granular flows contrasts with the simple non-slip boundary condition in ordinary fluids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Common boundary conditions at the base include flat, bumpy, and erodible bases, among wihch the bumpy base attracts most
attentions in both experimental and numerical studies of granular flows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bumpiness of a boundary made of glued/fix particles depends not only on the
size ratio between base and flow particles, but also the packing and layering of the
base particles. The situation becomes more complicated if bi-dispersity exists in the bulk
flows, which changes the relative roughness as segregation takes place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the continuum modeling of granular flows, the boundary condition is an important closure
to the governing equations, which requirs the knowledge of slip/non-slip condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project aims to understand the effect of base roughness in granular flows. The
geometric roughness of a base made of spheres is first characterized, with a wide range
of particle size and packing arrangement &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#jing_characterization_2016&quot;&gt;(Jing et al., 2016)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- To study the base roughness encountered in the modeling of granular flows. --&gt;
&lt;!-- 
Why important
- base roughness is important; boundary condition is difficult in granular flow

The dynamics of granular flows depend significantly on the nature of their boundaries. Geometric roughness at the base, 

- an important closure to the modeling of granular flow
- affect static-dynamic transition; affect segregation (feedback effect)

Aim of the project

What we have done --&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;jing_characterization_2016&quot;&gt;Jing, L., Kwok, C. Y., Leung, Y. F., &amp;amp; Sobral, Y. D. (2016). Characterization of base roughness for granular chute flows. &lt;i&gt;Physical Review E&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;94&lt;/i&gt;(5), 052901. https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevE.94.052901&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">One way that a granular flow differs from ordinary fluids is that its dynamics depends largely on the conditions at solid boundaries. For instance, the minimum thickness necessary to sustain a steady flow is a function of base roughness; the slip occurring at the base can modify the bulk rheological behavior, which changes the disorder flow state to a crystallized structure. Such a complicated dependency on solid boundaries in granular flows contrasts with the simple non-slip boundary condition in ordinary fluids.</summary></entry></feed>