<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-19T09:43:11-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Dr. Jing</title><subtitle>Lu Jing (Louis), postdoc at Northwestern University. PhD, The University of Hong Kong (HKU), in geomechanics, geophysical fluid dynamics, and granular physics. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Granular segregation: from particle-scale physics to continuum modeling</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/project/2020/04/19/segregation-force.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Granular segregation: from particle-scale physics to continuum modeling" /><published>2020-04-19T23:20:51-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-19T23:20:51-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/project/2020/04/19/segregation-force</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/project/2020/04/19/segregation-force.html">&lt;p&gt;This research aims to advance fundamental understanding of granular segregation at the particle level and enhance predictive modeling of size and/or density segregation in various flow configurations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first result is particle-scale mechanisms of how large and small particles migrate, which exhibit completely different physics; see &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.118001&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, the force driving size and density segregation at the single intruder limit is being characterized using a virtual spring-based force meter in numerical simulations. A simple scaling law is proposed, which enables the first &lt;em&gt;a priori&lt;/em&gt; prediction of rising and sinking of large intruders in free surface granular flows. This &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1906.03303&quot;&gt;result&lt;/a&gt; is currently under review.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This research aims to advance fundamental understanding of granular segregation at the particle level and enhance predictive modeling of size and/or density segregation in various flow configurations.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rate-dependent sliding laws for long-runout granular avalanches</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/project/2018/04/06/sliding-law.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rate-dependent sliding laws for long-runout granular avalanches " /><published>2018-04-06T00:40:12-05:00</published><updated>2018-04-06T00:40:12-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/project/2018/04/06/sliding-law</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/project/2018/04/06/sliding-law.html">&lt;p&gt;Characterization of slip velocity for granular flows over inclines of different geometric roughness, ranging from flat to bumpy. Modeling the frictional boundary behaviors as rate-dependent sliding laws; that is, the basal shear stress is proportional to the basal normal stress by a factor (i.e., the basal friction coefficient) that depends on local shear rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- This project aims to understand the effect of base roughness in granular flows. The
geometric roughness of a base made of spheres is first characterized, with a wide range
of particle size and packing arrangement (check out [here][1]). 

[1]: http://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevE.94.052901  --&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Characterization of slip velocity for granular flows over inclines of different geometric roughness, ranging from flat to bumpy. Modeling the frictional boundary behaviors as rate-dependent sliding laws; that is, the basal shear stress is proportional to the basal normal stress by a factor (i.e., the basal friction coefficient) that depends on local shear rates.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dynamics of immersed granular flows</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/project/2017/03/17/immersed-granular-flow.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dynamics of immersed granular flows" /><published>2017-03-17T07:20:51-05:00</published><updated>2017-03-17T07:20:51-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/project/2017/03/17/immersed-granular-flow</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/project/2017/03/17/immersed-granular-flow.html">&lt;p&gt;This research aims to understand the dynamics of immersed granular flow. We use both coarse-grid and fully-resolved fluid-particle coupling approaches, combined with small-scale laboratory experiments, to look at granular column collapse problem in fluid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many parameters control the dynamics of immersed granular flow, including particle size, particle density, fluid density, fluid viscosity, column aspect ratio and column packing density. We are seeking for dimensionless parameters combining the effects of all these parameters, which are expect to capture different flow regimes where distinct flow dynamics are observed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This research aims to understand the dynamics of immersed granular flow. We use both coarse-grid and fully-resolved fluid-particle coupling approaches, combined with small-scale laboratory experiments, to look at granular column collapse problem in fluid.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Graphic overview of my PhD work</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/03/phd-thesis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Graphic overview of my PhD work" /><published>2017-01-03T20:00:55-06:00</published><updated>2017-01-03T20:00:55-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/03/phd-thesis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/01/03/phd-thesis.html">&lt;p&gt;Here is a graphic overview of my PhD &lt;a href=&quot;https://hub.hku.hk/handle/10722/241402&quot;&gt;thesis&lt;/a&gt;. It was designed to become a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.civil.hku.hk/newsletter/newsletter2017feb.pdf&quot;&gt;newsletter cover&lt;/a&gt; for Department of Civil Engineering, HKU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/files/overview.png&quot; alt=&quot;research_overview&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;width: 800px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The debris flow sketch, courtesy of Alessandro Leonardi, was adapted from his &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.3929/ethz-a-010542711&quot;&gt;thesis&lt;/a&gt; with permission.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Here is a graphic overview of my PhD thesis. It was designed to become a newsletter cover for Department of Civil Engineering, HKU.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Effects of base roughness in granular flows down inclines</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/project/2016/12/20/base-roughness.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Effects of base roughness in granular flows down inclines" /><published>2016-12-20T06:20:51-06:00</published><updated>2016-12-20T06:20:51-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/project/2016/12/20/base-roughness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/project/2016/12/20/base-roughness.html">&lt;p&gt;One way that a granular flow differs from ordinary fluids is that its dynamics depends
largely on the conditions at solid boundaries. For instance, the minimum thickness
necessary to sustain a steady flow is a function of base roughness;
the slip occurring at the base can modify the bulk rheological behavior, which changes
the disorder flow state to a crystallized structure. Such a complicated dependency on solid boundaries in
granular flows contrasts with the simple non-slip boundary condition in ordinary fluids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Common boundary conditions at the base include flat, bumpy, and erodible bases, among wihch the bumpy base attracts most
attentions in both experimental and numerical studies of granular flows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bumpiness of a boundary made of glued/fix particles depends not only on the
size ratio between base and flow particles, but also the packing and layering of the
base particles. The situation becomes more complicated if bi-dispersity exists in the bulk
flows, which changes the relative roughness as segregation takes place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the continuum modeling of granular flows, the boundary condition is an important closure
to the governing equations, which requirs the knowledge of slip/non-slip condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project aims to understand the effect of base roughness in granular flows. The
geometric roughness of a base made of spheres is first characterized, with a wide range
of particle size and packing arrangement &lt;a class=&quot;citation&quot; href=&quot;#jing_characterization_2016&quot;&gt;(Jing et al., 2016)&lt;/a&gt;; link is &lt;a href=&quot;http://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevE.94.052901&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- To study the base roughness encountered in the modeling of granular flows. --&gt;
&lt;!-- 
Why important
- base roughness is important; boundary condition is difficult in granular flow

The dynamics of granular flows depend significantly on the nature of their boundaries. Geometric roughness at the base, 

- an important closure to the modeling of granular flow
- affect static-dynamic transition; affect segregation (feedback effect)

Aim of the project

What we have done --&gt;

&lt;ol class=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;jing_characterization_2016&quot;&gt;Jing, L., Kwok, C. Y., Leung, Y. F., &amp;amp; Sobral, Y. D. (2016). Characterization of base roughness for granular chute flows. &lt;i&gt;Physical Review E&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;94&lt;/i&gt;(5), 052901. https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevE.94.052901&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">One way that a granular flow differs from ordinary fluids is that its dynamics depends largely on the conditions at solid boundaries. For instance, the minimum thickness necessary to sustain a steady flow is a function of base roughness; the slip occurring at the base can modify the bulk rheological behavior, which changes the disorder flow state to a crystallized structure. Such a complicated dependency on solid boundaries in granular flows contrasts with the simple non-slip boundary condition in ordinary fluids.</summary></entry></feed>